Web Developer

Email: michaelcheng022@gmail.com Mobile: (626) 731 - 0459

SUMMARY

Recent college graduate freelancing as a junior web developer specializing in front end development. Have taken computer science classes in college as well as online bootcamp courses over the past year. Strong background in customer and team relations. Currently searching for any opportunity to gain experience as a developer in the tech industry.

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: JavaScript, Python, HTML5
- Technologies/Skills: CSS, Bootstrap, React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, NPM, jQuery, REST API, Git and GitBash, ES6

EXPERIENCE

Lead Technician Assistant

Superior Technology Services, Inc., Los Angeles, CA June 2010 – Aug 2016

- Scheduled appointments to ensure business kept flowing
- Managed invoices to keep record of company spending and profits
- Directly interacted with high profile clients to ensure customer satisfaction
- Worked on projects that involved complete digital renovations of large dental offices
- Assisted main technician in tasks requiring in-depth knowledge of computer hardware and software

Freelance Developer

Jan 2019 - Present

- Currently working on a website showcase art portfolio and online shop for a private client
- Showcasing art gallery using technologies of HTML, CSS, JS, Bootstrap 4
- Implementing backend technologies for shop functionality

PERSONAL PROJECTS

RGB Guessing Game

A simple guessing game using RGB color system

- Helps users get more familiar with RGB color system
- Demonstrates knowledge of advanced DOM manipulation and functional programming

YelpCamp

Basic Yelp Clone that allows users to upload and view various campsites including prices, location and reviews

- Demonstrates knowledge of Object Oriented Programming and modular programming
- Incorporates user authentication middleware through the use of Passport.js
- Implemented backend NodeJS webbook and uses MongoDB hosted on Heroku

Web Portfolio

A personal portfolio website

- Created with HTML, CSS, and Javascript to create a minimalistic theme.
- Utilized the web design libraries jQuery and Bootstrap for responsive pages and mobile-compatibility.

EDUCATION

University of California - Riverside

BA, Economics Administrations w/ Information Systems Concentration Sept 2014 – Dec 2018

Relevant coursework: Intro to Computer Science, Object Oriented Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms